Eric A. Eaton Papers VHP2005/15
CCSU Veterans History Project
Eric A. Eaton Papers
Bulk, 1987-1993
1987 - 1993, 2005
VHP2005/15
CCSU Veterans History Project
359.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
The collection describe Eric Eaton's military experince during 1st Persian Gulf war (Operation Desert Storm) with U.S. Marine Corps. Materials in collection include oral history interview, two books about U.S. Marine unit and divison history, and photographs taken in Saudi Arabia and Kuwait.
Eaton, Eric A., (Eric Allan), 1969 -
Biographical/Historical note
Eric Eaton enlisted in the Marine Corps the day after his 16th birthday in 1985. Because of his young age he had to sign up for the delayed entry program, which meant that he wouldn't go to boot camp until his graduation from high school. In June of 1987, he traveled to Parris Island, SC for boot camp which lasted for 3 months. When he signed up for the Marine Corps for six years, he was guaranteed to be in the infantry. After boot camp, he was sent to Camp Geiger (part of Camp Lejeune, NC) where he went to the school of infantry for advanced infantry training for over three months. Eaton's specialty was with anti-tank missiles. From there Eaton went to Camp Pendleton in San Diego, CA, and then on a flyover to Okinawa which lasted for six months. In August of 1990, he went on leave for 15 days, and when he returned his unit immediately began desert training so they could be shipped to Saudi Arabia, for Operation Desert Shield. Eaton gives a very detailed description of what the marines experienced in Saudi Arabia and the escalation of events that led to war. By January of 1991, the air war began, and Eaton's unit thought they would be fighting often, however, a cease fire was called on March 1, 1991. Eaton describes the feeling of disappointment that the troops did not go into Iraq, which made them feel as if the "job was unfinished". Eaton's unit arrived at Camp Pendleton around May of 1991 to a celebration of their return and their success in the Middle East. Eaton remained in the Marine Corps until June of 1993, although he wished to remain in the Marine Corps, the government was downsizing the military, and the option to remain in the Corps was not available. Eaton then moved back to his hometown of East Hartford, CT, and used the G.I. Bill to attend Manchester Community College and CCSU. He became certified to teach in 1997 and has been teaching history since then.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Technical metadata of digital objects are extracted and encoded in PREMIS preservation metadata format
Preservation Metadata
United States. Marine Corps. Marines, 1st. .; United States. Marine Corps.; Camp Lejeune (N.C.); Camp Pendleton (Calif.); Interviews; Kuwait; Manuscript; Okinawa-shi (Japan); Parris Island (S.C.); Persian Gulf War, 1991 -- Personal narratives, American; Persian Gulf War, 1991.; Photographs; Saudi Arabia
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2005/15.I
  - Marine Corps Meritorious Mast Certificate, Dec. 2, 1991; VHP2005/15.I.1
  - Eric Eaton’s Promotion to Sergeant, Nov. 1, 1992; VHP2005/15.I.2
  - Interview Synopsis, Dec. 3, 2005; VHP2005/15.I.3; 3.0 pages
- Series II: Publications, VHP2005/15.II
  - Book of the 13th Marine Expeditionary Unit, n.d.; VHP2005/15.II.1; 192.0 Digital objects
  - Liberators of Kuwait City: 1st Marine Division, Desert Shield and Desert Storm (book), 1992; VHP2005/15.II.2; 133.0 Digital objects
- Series III: Multi-Media, VHP2005/15.III
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2005/15.III
    - Eric Eaton in U.S. Marine dress uniform. Parris Island, SC, 1987; VHP2005/15.III.1; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton, advanced infantry training at Camp Lejeune, NC, 1987; VHP2005/15.III.2; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton, advanced infantry training at Camp Lejeune, NC, 1987; VHP2005/15.III.3; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton, D Company 1/1. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1987; VHP2005/15.III.4; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton. School of Infantry. Camp Lejeune, NC, 1987; VHP2005/15.III.5; 133.0
    - Olongapo City, Philippines. Eric Eaton's first flyover, 1988; VHP2005/15.III.6; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton Just got tattoo, Philippines, 1989; VHP2005/15.III.7; 133.0
    - Four marines in living quater, Philipines, 1989; VHP2005/15.III.8; 133.0
      General note
      Persons left to right: James Graham, Rick Kuhn, Eric Eaton, Mark Henderson
    - U.S.S. Peleliu on deployment to West Pacific, 1989; VHP2005/15.III.9; 133.0
    - shipboard living quarters, U.S.S. Peleliu, 1989; VHP2005/15.III.10; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton in "Team Spirit" joint military training exercise. South Korea, 1990; VHP2005/15.III.11; 133.0
    - Mobile Army Surgical Hospital (MASH unit) - Pasco Pier, South Korea, 1990; VHP2005/15.III.12; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton tieing a boot. Camp Pendleton, Oceanside, CA, 1990; VHP2005/15.III.13; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1990; VHP2005/15.III.14; 133.0
    - Eric & Inez Eaton Marine Corps ball. Camp Pendleton, Oceanside, CA, Nov. 1991; VHP2005/15.III.15; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton in Marines dress uniform. Camp Pendleton, CA, Nov. 1991; VHP2005/15.III.16; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton. Camp Pendleton, Oceanside, CA, 1991; VHP2005/15.III.17; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1991; VHP2005/15.III.18; 133.0
    - Three marines posted in front of destroyed tank. Kuwait, 1991; VHP2005/15.III.19; 133.0
      (from left to right) PFC Villanueva, PFC Wicka, Eric Eaton
    - Marines of D Company 1/1 in victory Parade in San Diego, CA, 1991; VHP2005/15.III.20; 133.0
    - Victory Parade for operation Desert Storm in San Diego, CA, 1991; VHP2005/15.III.21; 133.0
    - Victory Parade for operation Desert Storm in San Diego, CA, 1991; VHP2005/15.III.22; 133.0
    - Eric & Inez Eaton. Return from Desert Storm, April 1991; VHP2005/15.III.23; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton Return from Desert Storm, 1991; VHP2005/15.III.24; 133.0
    - Eric Eaton's family and friends after return from Desert Storm Welcome Home. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1991; VHP2005/15.III.25; 133.0
      Persons left to right: Melissa Reed, Inez Eaton, Melissa Gary, Jennifer Kuhn
    - Eric Eaton. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1992; VHP2005/15.III.26
    - Eric Eaton with teddy bear, on board U.S.S. Okinawa, 1992; VHP2005/15.III.27
    - Eric Eaton. Camp Pendleton, CA, 1993; VHP2005/15.III.28
    - Eric Eaton at his resident. East Hartford, CT, 2005; VHP2005/15.III.29
  - Subseries B: Moving Images, VHP2005/15.IIIb
    - Oral history interview, Dec. 3, 2005; VHP2005/15.IIIb.1; 1.0 dvd; Hurst, Eileen (Disk DVD VHP2005/15, Box VHP Interview #1)